The Architecture type we will be using is a combination of MVC and Component-based.


	When creating a complex software system, it is essential to have a common abstraction of the system onto which all other elements can be built. This common abstraction (in the case of software projects such as the one being outlined in this document) is called software architecture. Software architecture is a starting point whose goal is to allow even laymen to the software the ability to understand the over-arcing concepts and major functions of a complex system without having to learn the inner intricacies. A parallel to software architecture that highlights the importance and function of a well described common abstraction is the way in which large businesses are structured. Every department has a clearly defined general role, and each department falls within a larger interdependent system, which is the business itself. This layer of general abstraction allows naive onlookers to understand that a business has portions relating to customer service, human resources, management, ect without knowing what individual a customer�s service representative does in their daily tasks or what the duties of a manager is.
	As software architecture is a building point for the rest of the system, carful consideration should be take to allow a system to achieve what it was intended to achieve. This is done by first identifying and describing general purpose functions (not to be confused with programing functions as that is far to narrow a base for the current stage of planning) that a system should be able to achieve if it is to meet minimum requirements.
      In the tank system, such general functions can be described as standard suites of like systems previously built (strategies games such as Civilization or Europa Universalis). The most apparent when thinking of the tank system is its ability to display information to a user. As the system�s main function is not to simply display static information, the system should also have the ability to gather input from the user. This input must then be acting on some dynamic data set, or else the users input would become pointless. Also, considerations to the AI and server system must be taken into consideration as they have a major role in the fulfilment of basic functionality. These different components are numerous and it is confusing to see how any one must interact with one another. Now then, is the time to start discussing specific architecture.
      Considering the general functions of the tanks system, the architecture that best suites the system is layered architecture with a Model-View-Control design patter. This singular architecture however fails to encapsulate all our needs as no part is dedicated to server based systems, nor does any part facilitate the needs of the AI, which are specific to a forth (programming language) style environment. Thus, two additional component-based architecture style elements are needed to service these two system specific pieces. The resulting architecture facilitates all the basic functions of the tank system; It can present a GUI through the view, interface between the player and the system through the control, store any changes the player�s input has on the system and through the two new elements it can supply the AI with a distinct forth environment which it requires and abstracts server communication into a single functional object (not to be confused with java object) for ease of use.
      When considering why the hybrid Model-View-Control (from now on referred to as MVC) is a possible fit for the tanks system, one should consider alternative systems and how they lack the support MVC provides. 
      A conceptually simplistic design to start the comparison with is a monolithic architecture. In this architecture style, all functions are handled on a single tier and provides no modularity. This architecture style�s strength lie in its self-contained, independent nature and are easier to test as there is no communication between modules. However, this architecture type is unsuitable for our system for a variety of reasons. First and foremost is monolithic systems difficulty with multiple language implementation. As our system requires a forth style environment for the AI, as well parts tailored to JSON files for server communication. As monolithic systems require everything to be tightly-coupled and all contained within the same structure, implementation of these components that require different programming languages than the rest of the system becomes extremely difficult. In the MVC implementation, these difficulties are not present due to the less tightly coupled nature of MVC and the addition of the component-based structure. Secondly, with monolithic architecture, division of labour on the singular structure in the system becomes difficult. It is no longer the case where an individual or a group of individuals can independently work on a portion of the architecture without affecting the entire system. With a more modelized architecture, such as typical Model-View-Control or Three-tier architecture, an individual could work on a specific element of the system due to it not being strongly dependant on the rest of the system.


