Class Description for End:

       The class End is a view or display class that would tend to run at the end of a play session. The main function of End is to display all information and options that would be helpful to a player at the end of a play session. Information that would be displayed would be statistics gathered over the course of the game, such as which teams did the most damage, which teams moved the most, and a bar graph breakdown of how many turns each team�s tanks survived to. It would then display underneath the general statistical breakdown, a more specific one based on the teams controlled by player. Theses stats would be tank specific, so a overview of individual tank performance can be seen. Finally, at the bottom of the display, a button for exit, main menu, and save team stats are found. The Exit button exits the program, the main menu button will bring switch back to the main menu view, and the save team stats will upload each tank individual stats to the server for future reference, then switch to the main menu view. 
